Date of birth: 15th February 1982

Nationality: French

ORCID: 0000-0001-9006-8436

NIH BioSketch

Github organization: github.com/IARCbioinfo Website: www.rarecancersgenomics.com

Computational Cancers Genomics Team Genomic Epidemiology Branch International Agency for Research on Cancer (IARC-WHO) 25 avenue Tony Garnier, 69007 Lyon, France

Email: follm@iarc.who.int

Research Group: www.iarc.who.int/teams-ccg/

# **Professional Appointments**

2021-on	Team Leader, International Agency for Research on Cancer (IARC-WHO), Lyon, France
2014-2020	Scientist, International Agency for Research on Cancer (IARC-WHO), Lyon, France
2012-2014	Staff Research Scientist, Swiss Federal Institute of Technology, Lausanne, Switzerland
2007-2012	Postdoctoral Researcher, Institute of Ecology and Evolution, University of Berne, Switzerland

### Honors and awards

2024-on	pathology, International Agency for Research on Cancer (IARC-WHO), tumourclassification.iarc.who.int/									
2023	Young investigator award, International Mesothelioma Interest Group (iMig), imig.org									
2022-2024	<b>Chair of the Rare Cancers Working Group</b> , European Prospective Investigation into Cancer and Nutrition (EPIC), epic.iarc.who.int									
2022-on	Chair of the Data Science Steering Committee, International Agency for Research on Cancer (IARC-WHO)									
2021-on	<b>Chair of the Health Technologies Pillar</b> , Scientific Steering Committee of the Lyon Auvergne Rhône-Alpes Canceropole (CLARA), www.canceropole-clara.com									
2021-on	lung NET task force member, European NEuroendocrine Tumors Society (ENETS), www.enets.org									
2016-on	<b>Scientific Committee member</b> , French MESOBANK (virtual mesothelioma national biobank), www.netmeso.fr/netmeso/mesopath-et-mesobank									

where of the WUO electrication of turmours 6th adition subsemmittee on a

## Education

2004-2007	PhD	in	<b>Population</b>	Genetics	and	Evolution,	University	of	Grenoble,	France.
theses.hal.science/tel-00216192/										

2001–2004 **MSc Computer science and Applied Mathematics, specialization in Bioinformatics**, Grenoble Institute of Technology ENSIMAG, Grenoble, France.

### Personal Statement

I am a computational biologist with extensive training in applied mathematics, computer science, bioinformatics, and statistical genetics. During my doctoral and postdoctoral training, I focused on developing new statistical and computational methods to analyze large genomic datasets, including approaches for Bayesian inference, population genetics, and variant detection. Over the past decade, I have led interdisciplinary teams integrating genomics, transcriptomics, and pathology imaging data to advance translational cancer research, with a particular focus on thoracic tumors. In addition to my role as Team Leader, I also coordinate the bioinformatics efforts at the International Agency for Research on Cancer (IARC-WHO). In 2015, I created the Rare Cancers Genomics initiative together with Dr. Lynnette Fernandez-Cuesta. As part of these efforts, I have developed and supervised multiple open-source software projects aimed at ultra-sensitive variant calling, integrative multi-omics pipelines, and deep-learning-based image analysis.

### **Publications**

83 publications in international peer-reviewed scientific journals, including 9 publications as first/co-first author, and 16 publications as last/co-last/corresponding author. Full list available at Google Scholar and My NCBI Bibliography.

h-index: 45 (source: Google Scholar); mean NIH iCite Relative Citation Ratio: 3.35 (RCR, indicating that my publications have received, on average, 3.35 times as many citations per year as the median NIH-funded papers in their fields).

Named a 2024 Top Scholar by ScholarGPS (top 0.5% of all scholars worldwide) in Genomics and Genotyping